<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ACM CHI on ULRIK LYNGS</title>
    <link>/categories/acm-chi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ACM CHI on ULRIK LYNGS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/acm-chi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R packages for CHI papers with R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2018/10/29/r-packages-for-chi-papers-with-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/10/29/r-packages-for-chi-papers-with-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>So, I previously wrote at great length about how to use the ACM Master Article LaTeX templates (or any other LaTeX templates) in tandem with R Markdown to write transparent and reproducible papers.
To make it speedy and easy in practice specifically in relation to the ACM CHI Conference, I ended up creating two R packages which provides R Markdown templates for submissions in the latest formats for ACM CHI Proceedings as well as ACM CHI Extended Abstracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write ACM Articles with R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/18/how-to-write-acm-articles-with-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/18/how-to-write-acm-articles-with-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: After writing this post, I created two R packages which add R Markdown templates for CHI Proceedings and CHI Extended Abstract manuscript to RStudio. They implement the steps detailed in this post (and more) and provide examples within the sample content.
I love R Markdown. I use R for almost all my data analyses and visualisations, and Rmd files help me keep an interactive lab notebook of the steps I took while making it quick and easy to reproduce everything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>