<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reproducibility on ULRIK LYNGS</title>
    <link>/categories/reproducibility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reproducibility on ULRIK LYNGS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/reproducibility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create New Chunk Options in R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/03/how-to-create-new-chunk-options-in-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/03/how-to-create-new-chunk-options-in-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>For the 2019 ACM CHI conference I wanted to go all in on reproducibility by writing our paper submission completely in R Markdown and knit to PDF via the ACM’s LaTeX template. It worked in the end (the source file for our paper is here, an R package with our template is here, and a related blog post is here).
However, one of the challenges along the way was that I was missing chunk options to be able to set all the necessary parameters from R Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R packages for CHI papers with R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2018/10/29/r-packages-for-chi-papers-with-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/10/29/r-packages-for-chi-papers-with-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>So, I previously wrote at great length about how to use the ACM Master Article LaTeX templates (or any other LaTeX templates) in tandem with R Markdown to write transparent and reproducible papers.
To make it speedy and easy in practice specifically in relation to the ACM CHI Conference, I ended up creating two R packages which provides R Markdown templates for submissions in the latest formats for ACM CHI Proceedings as well as ACM CHI Extended Abstracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write ACM Articles with R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2018/07/18/how-to-write-acm-articles-with-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/07/18/how-to-write-acm-articles-with-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: After writing this post, I created two R packages which add R Markdown templates for CHI Proceedings and CHI Extended Abstract manuscript to RStudio. They implement the steps detailed in this post (and more) and provide examples within the sample content.
I love R Markdown. I use R for almost all my data analyses and visualisations, and Rmd files help me keep an interactive lab notebook of the steps I took while making it quick and easy to reproduce everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digging Science Out of a Hole: The Reproducibility Index</title>
      <link>/post/2016/09/26/digging-science-out-of-a-hole-the-reproducibility-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016/09/26/digging-science-out-of-a-hole-the-reproducibility-index/</guid>
      <description>Note: After I wrote this blog post, helpful folks over at PsychMAP shared some excellent initiatives that address the same issue: Curate Science is a crowdsourced collection and annotation of replications, and Pub Peer is a browser plug-in that gives you other researchers’ comments on the article you’re reading. Check them out!
Science is in trouble. For decades, we have paid lip service to the notion that scientific knowledge can be trusted because it is reproducible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>